Olubunmi Ruth Alao

♦ http://bumsyalao.me/ ■ bumsyalao@gmail.com ♦ /bumsyalao 🛅 /bumsyalao 📞 +971501507152

3+ years of experience in web application development, working mostly with JavaScript; React as frontend framework and NodeJS as backend solution. I understand business requirements, prioritise work based on highest business value and work with teams to solve problems.

Relevant Experience

Software Developer (contractor) at IBM

Dec 2018 - Present

Remote & Freelancing

Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

I worked on the TAMM Project here In Abu Dhabi. It is an impactful project aiming to revolutionise how citizens of Abu Dhabi interact with government services.

Building Full stack applications using Micro-service for frontend and backend architecture while following agile software programming practices.

Writing Frontend and Backend tests



Working remotely with engineering teams to build web applications SCSS TDD NodeJS React Redux Javascript ES6

Webpack AWS MongoDB Docker

Software Developer at Andela NG

Aug 2017 - Feb 2018

Building Full stack application using Micro-service for frontend and backend architecture while following agile software programming practices.

Writing Front-end, Back-end and E2E test.

Contributed to Reaction commerce open source.

Contributed to Cards For Humanity, a fast-paced online version of the popular card game, Cards Against Humanity.



EFT Specialist at Interswitch NG

Jan 2016 - Aug 2017

Full FEP Deployment, Upgrades, Maintenance & Support of core banking systems (Postilion, Postcard, Postilion Office).

HSM (Hardware Security Module) Deployment.

Channel Enhancement & Certification (ATM, POS, WEB, Mobile, EMV Certification).

Integration to external systems, parties and networks. Examples include: Integration to Processors/Switches (MasterCard, VISA, VERVE).

Installing, managing, upgrading and administering Microsoft SQL databases

Postilion MSSQL interswitch.com

Education

Selected Personal Projects Ideabox 2017 2017 Post-It Ideabox is a simple application that allows users to create a pool of Post-it is a simple application that allows users create groups and ideas and promote collaboration. post messages to group. React Redux SCSS NodeJS Mongoose Javascript ES6 ideabox NodeJS | React | [Redux] SCSS PostgresSQL Javascript ES6 S post-it **Flames** 2018 Diary 2017 A game of love and prediction. A python/django playground. HTML CSS Javascript SFlames Django S Diary Python **Selected Awards and Certifications** Front-End Web Developer **Microsoft Certified Professional** 2018 2016 Udacity Microsoft License 13392204 **Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification** Python-codecademy 2017 2017 Codecademy See certificate 2016 **Postilion Basic Traning**

2010 - 2014

Covenant University

CGPA: 4.43/5

ACI worldwide

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

Visualization and Topological Analysis.

Final year project: A Computing Platform for Metabolic Network